# **Nitish Kumar Patel**

# **Frontend Developer**

**Location**: Garhwa, Jharkhand. India.

**Mob:** +91-9140100614

Email: nitishpatel404@gmail.com

**Github**: <a href="https://github.com/nitishpatel404">https://github.com/nitishpatel404</a> **LinkedIn:** <a href="mailto:linkedin.com/in/nitish-patel-">linkedin.com/in/nitish-patel-</a>

192950a2/

Well-qualified frontend developer, familiar with a wide range of programming utilities. familiar with UI part and API integration requirements. Handles any part of the process with ease.

Collaborative team player with excellent technical abilities. Offering 4 years of relevant experience.

## RECENT PROJECT

# 1. Item Banking: -

**Project Summary:** It's a web app that has different modules like an assignment module, a user module, a login module, a role module, an asset module, etc. The main purpose of this project is to generate questions for different exams after the verification of all these modules.

**My Contribution:** I worked on the asset module for creating assets after uploading audio, video, and images. After creating assets, the manager can view, update, delete, and swap assets. I also worked on the global style part for all modules and the UI and functional

### 2. Black Box: -

**Project Summary:** It's a video conferencing web app that allows users to connect with video, audio, phone, and chat. It's developed using the Twilio Video API and the TokBox Video API.

**My Contribution:** - I worked on adding the raise hand functionality during calls, mute and unmute functionality, room creation for users, dominant speaker (identifying who is speaking), message notification and count during chat, a background image for users, and different small features.

# **SKILLS**

- Angular
- Type Script
- Java Script
- Git
- HTML
- CSS
- ReactJS
- Java Basic
- WordPress
- Professional Communication
- Team management

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

# **Full Stack Web Development**

Newton School Issued: April-2022

## **EDUCATION**

Dr. A.P.J. Abdul Kalam Technical University Uttar Pradesh, Lucknow.

B. Tech, Computer Science & Engineering (2013–2017)

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### **1. Exam Room AI**— Frontend Engineer

April 2022 - Present (12 months)
Angular, Typescript, JavaScript, Html, CSS

### 2. APS Tech Mart & Cross Ace— Web Developer

May 2020 – Aug 2021(1 year 4 months, Part time and freelancer)

WordPress, CSS

# 3. Pango Retail— Web Developer

April 2018 - Nov 2019(1 year 8 months)

WordPress, CSS